<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/ns/ttml" xmlns:ttp="http://www.w3.org/ns/ttml#parameter" ttp:timeBase="media" xmlns:tts="http://www.w3.org/ns/ttml#style" xml:lang="en" xmlns:ttm="http://www.w3.org/ns/ttml#metadata">
  <head>
    <metadata>
      <ttm:title></ttm:title>
    </metadata>
    <styling>
      <style id="s0" tts:backgroundColor="black" tts:fontStyle="normal" tts:fontSize="16" tts:fontFamily="sansSerif" tts:color="white" />
    </styling>
  </head>
  <body style="s0">
    <div>
      <p begin="9.466s" id="p0" end="13.266s">Neal Ewers: Many of you watching this have normal vision.</p>
      <p begin="13.266s" id="p1" end="17.599s">Oh sure, you might have to find your reading glasses if you want to read a good book</p>
      <p begin="17.6s" id="p2" end="21.066s">and you might have to make sure there’s enough light around to see it.</p>
      <p begin="21.066s" id="p3" end="24.532s">But for the most part, many of you see rather well.</p>
      <p begin="24.533s" id="p4" end="30.566s">For others, seeing things clearly isn’t quite so easy.</p>
      <p begin="30.566s" id="p5" end="35.299s">For example, how do people with less than perfect vision use the web?</p>
      <p begin="35.3s" id="p6" end="38.5s">What kind of technology is available?</p>
      <p begin="38.5s" id="p7" end="44.433s">And what can web designers do to make their pages easier to use by people who don’t see quite so clearly.</p>
      <p begin="44.433s" id="p8" end="51.433s">Vision loss can take many forms and it can be mild or quite extreme.</p>
      <p begin="51.433s" id="p9" end="55.499s">For example, some people have hypersensitivity to glare,</p>
      <p begin="55.5s" id="p10" end="59.066s">while others may be colorblind.</p>
      <p begin="59.066s" id="p11" end="62.366s">Some may see an entire image,</p>
      <p begin="62.366s" id="p12" end="64.399s">but it might be either blurred or clouded,</p>
      <p begin="64.4s" id="p13" end="67.4s">while others might see the center of the image</p>
      <p begin="67.4s" id="p14" end="69.4s">often referred to as tunnel vision.</p>
      <p begin="69.4s" id="p15" end="72.766s">And others still might see the edges of the image</p>
      <p begin="72.766s" id="p16" end="75.966s">often called peripheral vision.</p>
      <p begin="75.966s" id="p17" end="78.232s">Hello, my name is Neal Ewers,</p>
      <p begin="78.233s" id="p18" end="81.033s">and I work for the Trace Research and Development Center,</p>
      <p begin="81.033s" id="p19" end="83.966s">which is a part of the University of Wisconsin-Madison.</p>
      <p begin="83.966s" id="p20" end="87.932s">I too happen to have a vision condition.</p>
      <p begin="87.933s" id="p21" end="90.266s">I am totally blind.</p>
      <p begin="90.266s" id="p22" end="93.232s">I have my friend John Klatt here today.</p>
      <p begin="93.233s" id="p23" end="95.299s">I’ve asked him to come and talk to us</p>
      <p begin="95.3s" id="p24" end="97.433s">about his specific vision condition,</p>
      <p begin="97.433s" id="p25" end="100.933s">and how he uses technology to access the web.</p>
      <p begin="100.933s" id="p26" end="103.166s">Hi John.  It’s good to have you.</p>
      <p begin="103.166s" id="p27" end="104.699s">John Klatt: Hi Neal.  Thank you for having me.</p>
      <p begin="104.7s" id="p28" end="107.9s">Neal: Can you begin by telling us a little bit about who you are,</p>
      <p begin="107.9s" id="p29" end="111.866s">and how you do use technology to access the web?</p>
      <p begin="111.866s" id="p30" end="116.599s">John: Sure.  I’m a graduate student here at U.W.  I’m also employed by the University.</p>
      <p begin="116.6s" id="p31" end="122.7s">I have a form of macular degeneration that has taken a good part of my central vision.</p>
      <p begin="122.7s" id="p32" end="126.066s">And although my visual acuity is below 20/200,</p>
      <p begin="126.066s" id="p33" end="129.566s">I’m usually able to use most printed material</p>
      <p begin="129.566s" id="p34" end="134.699s">such as web pages as long as they’re blown up by a power of four.</p>
      <p begin="134.7s" id="p35" end="139.833s">I can show you briefly how I navigate not only computer technology,</p>
      <p begin="139.833s" id="p36" end="142.066s">but specifically the web.</p>
      <p begin="142.066s" id="p37" end="144.732s">I use a screen enlargement program called ZoomText,</p>
      <p begin="144.733s" id="p38" end="149.133s">and as you can see it enlarges everything on the screen.</p>
      <p begin="149.133s" id="p39" end="153.366s">It makes everything, all of the print nice and big and easy to read.</p>
      <p begin="153.366s" id="p40" end="157.066s">One of the features that I like about ZoomText</p>
      <p begin="157.066s" id="p41" end="158.966s">is that it comes with a couple of different options.</p>
      <p begin="158.966s" id="p42" end="161.666s">One of the problems with having this screen so large</p>
      <p begin="161.666s" id="p43" end="166.399s">is that only a portion of the screen actually fits on to my monitor at one time.</p>
      <p begin="166.4s" id="p44" end="167.666s">Neal: Ooh!</p>
      <p begin="167.666s" id="p45" end="173.499s">John: So it’s very easy to kind of become disoriented or lose track of where I am.</p>
      <p begin="173.5s" id="p46" end="177.333s">Neal: John, the reason I said ooh was the fact</p>
      <p begin="177.333s" id="p47" end="181.799s">that I realized that when you zoom as highly as you can zoom,</p>
      <p begin="181.8s" id="p48" end="187.966s">you must only be able to read one or two or three words at a time and that’s kind of like what happens to me</p>
      <p begin="187.966s" id="p49" end="192.399s">when I use my screen reader which speaks and therefore I only hear one word at a time.</p>
      <p begin="192.4s" id="p50" end="195.933s">So, I would guess that if you had vision low enough</p>
      <p begin="195.933s" id="p51" end="199.666s">to have to have that kind of magnification,</p>
      <p begin="199.666s" id="p52" end="202.766s">it would be really hard to figure out what was on the screen.</p>
      <p begin="202.766s" id="p53" end="206.532s">John: It can become very difficult, especially as the magnification goes up.</p>
      <p begin="206.533s" id="p54" end="211.766s">I can adjust the magnification so that essentially</p>
      <p begin="211.766s" id="p55" end="215.466s">one word or just two numbers are fitting on the screen</p>
      <p begin="215.466s" id="p56" end="219.166s">and in those situations it becomes very disorienting.</p>
      <p begin="219.166s" id="p57" end="226.299s">One of the ways to get around that problem is to simply switch the function of the magnification.</p>
      <p begin="226.3s" id="p58" end="231.9s">This option is actually like a hand held magnifier where</p>
      <p begin="231.9s" id="p59" end="237.033s">only the portion under the magnifying box actually becomes magnified.</p>
      <p begin="237.033s" id="p60" end="241.533s">With this option I can actually see the entire document that I’m working on,</p>
      <p begin="241.533s" id="p61" end="243.299s">or the entire web page that I’m working with,</p>
      <p begin="243.3s" id="p62" end="249.533s">but at the same time I can magnify the pieces that I really need to see.</p>
      <p begin="249.533s" id="p63" end="253.166s">On this page, while I can’t see any of the exact text,</p>
      <p begin="253.166s" id="p64" end="256.766s">I can tell that there’s a column of information on the left,</p>
      <p begin="256.766s" id="p65" end="260.932s">there appears to be a column of more detailed information on the right,</p>
      <p begin="260.933s" id="p66" end="266.533s">and up in the right hand corner it looks like there is something.</p>
      <p begin="266.533s" id="p67" end="268.166s">It could possibly be links.</p>
      <p begin="268.166s" id="p68" end="272.632s">I’m looking for pieces of information that give me context as to what the page is all about.</p>
      <p begin="272.633s" id="p69" end="279.499s">I’m also looking for pieces of information that match the context of the task I’m trying to complete.</p>
      <p begin="279.5s" id="p70" end="281.866s">Neal: John, can you give us an example?</p>
      <p begin="281.866s" id="p71" end="287.299s">John: Sure.  A couple of months ago I was doing a research project</p>
      <p begin="287.3s" id="p72" end="293.033s">using human subjects in research and this particular page is one that I came to quite often.</p>
      <p begin="293.033s" id="p73" end="296.899s">There are symbols next to each of these links.</p>
      <p begin="296.9s" id="p74" end="301.233s">And each of these symbols represents a different issue in human subject research.</p>
      <p begin="301.233s" id="p75" end="305.833s">And what I found is, after coming to the page a number of times, I no longer had to</p>
      <p begin="305.833s" id="p76" end="310.966s">start to differentiate between the headings and the descriptions of the headings and the various links.</p>
      <p begin="310.966s" id="p77" end="317.499s">All I needed to do was find the appropriate symbol and click on the link and I could access the page that I wanted.</p>
      <p begin="317.5s" id="p78" end="323.866s">This was a perfect example of how context can actually guide my tasks and can</p>
      <p begin="323.866s" id="p79" end="327.732s">actually facilitate the work that I’m doing.</p>
      <p begin="327.733s" id="p80" end="332.499s">Neal: John, do you use color at all to figure out how to get around a page?</p>
      <p begin="332.5s" id="p81" end="337.533s">John: Yeah, actually color is a pretty important element of the page.</p>
      <p begin="337.533s" id="p82" end="341.866s">On the UW home page up in the right hand corner there’s a list of links,</p>
      <p begin="341.866s" id="p83" end="348.932s">and the top row of links is in red and the row of links right below that is in orange.</p>
      <p begin="348.933s" id="p84" end="354.599s">It’s easy to distinguish between these links.  I don’t necessarily confuse them as one.</p>
      <p begin="354.6s" id="p85" end="357.633s">The screen magnifier obviously enlarges the text,</p>
      <p begin="357.633s" id="p86" end="361.699s">but it doesn’t necessarily prevent me from making simple mistakes.</p>
      <p begin="361.7s" id="p87" end="364.266s">I’m still not reading it real clearly,</p>
      <p begin="364.266s" id="p88" end="369.866s">and the simple use of color creates a distinction that is very helpful.</p>
      <p begin="369.866s" id="p89" end="374.599s">Neal: John, you can see color, but there are a number of people who are colorblind.</p>
      <p begin="374.6s" id="p90" end="379.166s">And if for example you went to a page that had stocks,</p>
      <p begin="379.166s" id="p91" end="383.666s">and the green ones were going up and the red ones were going down, you’d be lost.</p>
      <p begin="383.666s" id="p92" end="386.766s">John: Yeah, I certainly would and you are right,</p>
      <p begin="386.766s" id="p93" end="389.199s">I can distinguish the colors and that’s a big help for me.</p>
      <p begin="389.2s" id="p94" end="393.466s">For those people who are color blind, I know that some magnification software comes with</p>
      <p begin="393.466s" id="p95" end="397.499s">different settings that try to accommodate that.</p>
      <p begin="397.5s" id="p96" end="400.766s">They’ll filter in certain colors and filter out certain colors.</p>
      <p begin="400.766s" id="p97" end="406.732s">You can change the background setting, so there are some things that can be done.</p>
      <p begin="406.733s" id="p98" end="410.199s">Neal: What about spacing John?  Does the spacing of text</p>
      <p begin="410.2s" id="p99" end="413.466s">and other elements on a page help?</p>
      <p begin="413.466s" id="p100" end="416.366s">John: Yeah it really does.</p>
      <p begin="416.366s" id="p101" end="419.199s">Because of the way the magnification software works,</p>
      <p begin="419.2s" id="p102" end="424.533s">a little extra spacing between lines and a little extra spacing between links</p>
      <p begin="424.533s" id="p103" end="426.466s">actually helps me quite a bit.</p>
      <p begin="426.466s" id="p104" end="432.666s">When pages become too cluttered and there’s too much information packed into a small area,</p>
      <p begin="432.666s" id="p105" end="437.399s">it actually becomes fairly confusing to try to figure out what the text is saying and follow</p>
      <p begin="437.4s" id="p106" end="442.1s">where I am on a page, and honestly sometimes it becomes a little overwhelming.</p>
      <p begin="442.1s" id="p107" end="446.233s">This UW home page actually contains a great deal of information.</p>
      <p begin="446.233s" id="p108" end="449.666s">There are an awful lot of resources and links to other pages.</p>
      <p begin="449.666s" id="p109" end="452.332s">But as you can see there’s a tremendous amount of space.</p>
      <p begin="452.333s" id="p110" end="458.733s">There’s a lot of space between the lines, the print is nice and big even without the magnification software.</p>
      <p begin="458.733s" id="p111" end="463.966s">Things certainly do not look cluttered, and because of that I find it very easy to use.</p>
      <p begin="463.966s" id="p112" end="467.566s">Neal: Do you ever use shapes like blocks of text or boxes</p>
      <p begin="467.566s" id="p113" end="471.299s">or any thing like that to help get around.</p>
      <p begin="471.3s" id="p114" end="479.933s">John: Certainly, shapes are similar to color and space and that they help me understand what’s on the page.</p>
      <p begin="479.933s" id="p115" end="487.199s">Blocks of text, search bars positioned somewhere in the page give me clues as to</p>
      <p begin="487.2s" id="p116" end="490.333s">where to find particular things on the web page.</p>
      <p begin="490.333s" id="p117" end="495.466s">I think that web designers with some careful thought about</p>
      <p begin="495.466s" id="p118" end="500.866s">how they’re using color, shape, and space really help people navigate their task.</p>
      <p begin="500.866s" id="p119" end="504.132s">Neal: I know that your magnification software can speak</p>
      <p begin="504.133s" id="p120" end="508.866s">as well as magnify and it would seem to me that if you were losing a lot of your vision,</p>
      <p begin="508.866s" id="p121" end="513.499s">being able to hear something and see it at the same time would be really helpful.</p>
      <p begin="513.5s" id="p122" end="515.233s">Can you show us how that works?</p>
      <p begin="515.233s" id="p123" end="518.966s">John: Sure.  The magnification software that I use has something called the Doc Reader.</p>
      <p begin="518.966s" id="p124" end="523.166s">It will read all of the text on the page and at the same time</p>
      <p begin="523.166s" id="p125" end="525.766s">it will put the text on a ticker at the top of the page</p>
      <p begin="525.766s" id="p126" end="529.666s">so you get a chance to hear it as well as see it.</p>
      <p begin="529.666s" id="p127" end="533.532s">ZoomText Speech Synthesizer: Play button.  The University of Wisconsin Madison.</p>
      <p begin="533.533s" id="p128" end="535.733s">UW Search.  My UW. Quick links. Timetable.</p>
      <p begin="535.733s" id="p129" end="537.466s">Directories.  Employment.  Help.  News and Events.</p>
      <p begin="537.466s" id="p130" end="541.099s">Events Calendar. UW Madison to require…</p>
      <p begin="541.1s" id="p131" end="544.733s">John: One of the added benefits of having the text go through the ticker</p>
      <p begin="544.733s" id="p132" end="547.399s">is that all of the text becomes standardized.</p>
      <p begin="547.4s" id="p133" end="552.133s">So if the page has text that’s in a lot of different fonts,</p>
      <p begin="552.133s" id="p134" end="554.166s">or different sizes</p>
      <p begin="554.166s" id="p135" end="556.266s">or if it’s in red and difficult to read,</p>
      <p begin="556.266s" id="p136" end="558.299s">as it goes through the ticker it all becomes one size,</p>
      <p begin="558.3s" id="p137" end="562.5s">it becomes a style of font that’s very easy to read,</p>
      <p begin="562.5s" id="p138" end="565.333s">and it’s white text on a black background.</p>
      <p begin="565.333s" id="p139" end="570.366s">Neal: That would seem to be awful easy for lots of people with different conditions like colorblindness to use.</p>
      <p begin="570.366s" id="p140" end="572.432s">Can you use that without having it speak?</p>
      <p begin="572.433s" id="p141" end="581.233s">John: Yes and that’s actually the way I usually use it.</p>
      <p begin="581.233s" id="p142" end="581.866s">Neal: You mentioned font, John and I know that font size and font family are really important</p>
      <p begin="581.866s" id="p143" end="585.232s">and should be things that web developers keep in mind.</p>
      <p begin="585.233s" id="p144" end="588.966s">John: Yeah, I think you’re right and font color</p>
      <p begin="588.966s" id="p145" end="591.732s">and background are also important to me.</p>
      <p begin="591.733s" id="p146" end="594.733s">Neal: Well John, I have to say that you’ve certainly helped me,</p>
      <p begin="594.733s" id="p147" end="598.066s">a person who is totally blind, understand a lot more about</p>
      <p begin="598.066s" id="p148" end="601.766s">what it’s like for you to navigate the web.</p>
      <p begin="601.766s" id="p149" end="605.132s">And if you can show me, a totally blind person,</p>
      <p begin="605.133s" id="p150" end="609.499s">how it is, then you’ve obviously spoken to a lot of other people as well.</p>
      <p begin="609.5s" id="p151" end="611.566s">I really appreciate you being here.</p>
      <p begin="611.566s" id="p152" end="613.599s">John: Thank you for having me. I had a good time.</p>
    </div>
  </body>
</tt>